♪The autumn wind slips in, never asking when I'll return♪
♪ريح الخريف تتسلل، دون أن تسأل متى سأعود♪
♪Before the mirror, I comb my hair, lips parted just so♪
♪أمام المرآة، أمشط شعري، شفتاي مفتوحتان بهدوء♪
♪An old melody plays faintly, perhaps the answer to this life♪
♪لحن قديم يعزف بخفة، ربما هو جواب هذه الحياة♪
♪If fate leaves any trace at all♪
♪إذا كان القدر يترك أي أثر♪
♪Wild geese disappear in the woods, flowers wither at dusk♪
♪الإوز البري يختفي في الغابة، الزهور تذبل عند الغسق♪
♪How cruel the moonlight flooding the empty tower, wine growing cold♪
♪كم هو قاسٍ ضوء القمر الذي يغمر البرج الفارغ، والنبيذ يبرد♪
♪Long dreams and night rain tearing through the heart of Luoyang♪
♪أحلام طويلة ومطر الليل يمزق قلب لويانغ♪
♪Who still rides forth to keep a vow long left behind?♪
♪من لا يزال يركب ليفي بوعد طالما تركناه؟♪
♪Paint the love and the hate♪
♪ارسم الحب والكراهية♪
♪With gentle strokes of ink, like a lone wild goose flying far away♪
♪بضربات حبر لطيفة، مثل إوزة برية وحيدة تطير بعيدًا♪
♪Frost and snow to sketch memories, drawn taut like a bow♪
♪الصقيع والثلج لرسم الذكريات، مشدودة مثل القوس♪
♪One arrow dyed in deepest red♪
♪سهم واحد ملون بأحمر عميق♪
♪The bitter chill within my heart♪
♪البرد المرير في قلبي♪
♪The sorrow falling between your brows♪
♪الحزن الذي يسقط بين حاجبيك♪
♪Scalding memories lodged in my throat♪
♪ذكريات حارقة عالقة في حلقي♪
♪Burning away the warmth we once shared♪
♪تحرق الدفء الذي كنا نتشاركه♪
♪I would fade away with the candle's shadow♪
♪سأتلاشى مع ظل الشمعة♪
♪Sever the ties and stay behind alone♪
♪اقطع الروابط وابقَ وحيدًا♪
♪Let you go♪
♪دعك تذهب♪
♪Your sorrow lingers as you glance back♪
♪حزنك يبقى بينما تلقي نظرة للوراء♪
♪This longing has already worn me thin♪
♪هذا الشوق قد أضعفني بالفعل♪
♪We once vowed to grow old together♪
♪كنا نعد بأن نكبر معًا♪
♪But if fate bears no guilt, then why♪
♪ولكن إذا كان القدر لا يحمل ذنبًا، فلماذا♪
♪Does it play this song of tears for me alone?♪
♪يعزف هذه الأغنية من الدموع لي وحدي؟♪
=Destiny of Love= (Adapted from Lin Nan's novel, Destiny of Love.)
=قدر الحب= (مقتبس من رواية لين نان، قدر الحب.)
=Episode 8=
=الحلقة 8=
And if she wants to go out again tonight...
وإذا أرادت الخروج مرة أخرى الليلة...
Don't stop her.
لا توقفها.
Pretend you didn't see anything.
تصرف وكأنك لم ترَ شيئًا.
Understood.
فهمت.
Don't sleep tonight.
لا تنم الليلة.
I trust you the most.
أنا أثق بك أكثر.
Let's get something to eat once we finish our rounds.
لنحصل على شيء نأكله بعد أن ننتهي من جولاتنا.
Sure. What should we eat?
بالتأكيد. ماذا نأكل؟
Let's think about it.
لنفكر في الأمر.
You two.
أنتما الاثنان.
Come here.
تعالا إلى هنا.
The residence is secure.
المقر آمن.
Supper's on me tonight.
العشاء عليّ الليلة.
- Thanks, Feng.
- شكرًا، فنغ.
(Jiufeng really saved me tonight.)
(جيوفنغ أنقذني حقًا الليلة.)
(If I go through the main gate, Aliya won't have to wait too long.)
(إذا مررت من البوابة الرئيسية، لن تضطر عليا إلى الانتظار طويلاً.)
(He was going on about locking me up during the day.)
(كان يتحدث عن حبسي خلال النهار.)
(Well, I still snuck out.)
(حسنًا، ما زلت تسللت للخروج.)
(The heavens do favor the studious.)
(السماء تفضل المجتهدين.)
She left.
لقد غادرت.
(Benevolent and Kind)
(طيب القلب ولطيف)
Your Highness,
سموك،
why did you ask me to go to such lengths
لماذا طلبت مني أن أبذل كل هذا الجهد
for Her Highness?
من أجل سموها؟
I paid a visit to Everything Guild myself.
لقد قمت بزيارة نقابة "إيفريثينغ" بنفسي.
I learned from her brother that...
تعلمت من أخيها أن...
Who's that this late at night?
من هذا في وقت متأخر من الليل؟
What do you want?
ماذا تريد؟
Well...
حسنًا...
Do not be alarmed, Mr. Ji.
لا تنزعج، سيد جي.
I heard that Everything Guild solves all sorts of worldly troubles.
سمعت أن نقابة "إيفريثينغ" تحل جميع أنواع المشاكل الدنيوية.
I came
أتيت
in search of help.
بحثًا عن المساعدة.
My sister manages the guild.
أختي تدير النقابة.
She's not here right now.
إنها ليست هنا الآن.
But if you tell me your issue,
ولكن إذا أخبرتني بمشكلتك،
I'll pass it along
سأبلغها
when she returns.
عندما تعود.
That would be most appreciated.
سيكون ذلك موضع تقدير كبير.
Weren't you the one who needed help?
ألم تكن أنت من يحتاج إلى المساعدة؟
Why were you the one asking me all the questions?
لماذا كنت أنت من يطرح عليّ كل هذه الأسئلة؟
I'm tired.
أنا متعب.
I still have to continue tomorrow.
لا يزال عليّ أن أستمر غدًا.
Better head back early
من الأفضل أن أعود مبكرًا
so I can get a bit more sleep.
حتى أحصل على قليل من النوم.
(Prince Jin's Residence)
(مقر الأمير جين)
(Where are all the guards?)
(أين كل الحراس؟)
(Where did all these firefly lamps come from?)
(من أين أتت كل هذه المصابيح اليراع؟)
♪The clouds stretch endlessly across the sky♪
♪الغيوم تمتد بلا نهاية عبر السماء♪
♪Looking down at eyes that gaze into the distance♪
♪أنظر إلى العيون التي تحدق في البعيد♪
♪Time keeps moving on♪
♪الوقت يستمر في التقدم♪
♪Whose footprints are left behind?♪
♪من الذي ترك آثاره خلفه؟♪
♪It's more than just the courage to yearn♪
♪إنه أكثر من مجرد الشجاعة للشوق♪
♪It's destined that we cannot be close♪
♪مقدر لنا ألا نكون قريبين♪
♪Loving you is a secret♪
♪حبك سر♪
♪Afraid of disturbing you and then you'd distance yourself♪
♪أخشى أن أزعجك ثم تبتعد عني♪
♪Endlessly♪
♪بلا نهاية♪
♪How I wish I could dive into the sea♪
♪كم أتمنى أن أغطس في البحر♪
♪And gently rest♪
♪وأرتاح برفق♪
♪Is it to soothe the reason for your heart's pain♪
♪هل هو لتهدئة سبب ألم قلبك؟♪
♪If distance can't tear us apart and it's not hard to endure♪
♪إذا كانت المسافة لا يمكنها أن تفصلنا وليس من الصعب تحملها♪
♪Our tears will stay together♪
♪ستبقى دموعنا معًا♪
Fireflies, please help His Highness recover soon.
أيها اليراع، من فضلكم ساعدوا سموه على الشفاء قريبًا.
♪Don't forget the love they could never have♪
♪لا تنسوا الحب الذي لم يستطيعوا الحصول عليه♪
(Everything Guild)
(نقابة "إيفريثينغ")
Dear, you're here.
عزيزتي، أنتِ هنا.
What are you doing, Fang?
ماذا تفعلين يا فانغ؟
I'm giving myself acupuncture.
أنا أعالج نفسي بالإبر الصينية.
I can see that,
أستطيع رؤية ذلك،
but why?
لكن لماذا؟
Stimulating certain brain points helps
تحفيز نقاط معينة في الدماغ يساعد
with memory recovery.
على استعادة الذاكرة.
Did anything come back?
هل عاد أي شيء؟
I...
أنا...
I remember myself
أتذكر نفسي
in red,
باللون الأحمر،
running through a forest.
أجري عبر الغابة.
Anything else?
أي شيء آخر؟
Oh, right.
أوه، صحيح.
These vernacular stories.
هذه القصص العامية.
I've read them. More than once.
لقد قرأتها. أكثر من مرة.
You're my agent.
أنت وكيلتي.
Of course, you've read them.
بالطبع، لقد قرأتها.
I remember...
أتذكر...
Actually, I don't remember anything at all.
في الواقع، لا أتذكر أي شيء على الإطلاق.
But these books all feel familiar.
لكن هذه الكتب تبدو مألوفة.
And then?
ثم ماذا؟
That's it.
هذا كل شيء.
Maybe I should try a few more needles?
ربما يجب أن أجرب المزيد من الإبر؟
I'll just add a few more.
سأضيف المزيد فقط.
Fang!
فانغ!
What are you doing to yourself?
ماذا تفعلين بنفسك؟
You've turned yourself into a porcupine!
لقد حولت نفسك إلى قنفذ!
- What's going on? - Dad.
- ماذا يحدث؟ - أبي.
She's trying to recover her memory.
إنها تحاول استعادة ذاكرتها.
Recover her...
استعادة ذاكرتها...
You mustn't do that!
لا يجب أن تفعلي ذلك!
What I mean is,
ما أعنيه هو،
physicians can't treat themselves.
الأطباء لا يمكنهم علاج أنفسهم.
Don't worry, Dad.
لا تقلق يا أبي.
I know what I'm doing.
أعرف ما أفعله.
Feel anything?
هل تشعرين بأي شيء؟
Are any memories coming back?
هل تعود أي ذكريات؟
I think
أعتقد
I feel something.
أشعر بشيء ما.
What do you feel?
ماذا تشعرين؟
My head...
رأسي...
- Fang!
- فانغ!
What's wrong?
ماذا حدث؟
(Everything Guild) Dad, what's wrong with her?
(نقابة كل شيء) أبي، ما خطبها؟
Quickly!
بسرعة!
From now on, you keep an eye on her.
من الآن فصاعدًا، راقبيها.
No more of this memory-recovery nonsense.
لا مزيد من هذا الهراء حول استعادة الذاكرة.
Dad.
أبي.
Why are you so afraid of her
لماذا تخشى كثيرًا من أن تتذكر
remembering the past?
الماضي؟
I'm not.
أنا لست كذلك.
You silly child.
أنت طفل سخيف.
I'm just worried about her health.
أنا فقط قلقة على صحتها.
You saw her, right?
لقد رأيتها، أليس كذلك؟
Covering her whole head
رأسها مغطى بالكامل
in needles like that.
بالإبر هكذا.
She even fainted!
حتى أنها أغمي عليها!
What's more important?
ما هو الأهم؟
Regaining her memories or staying alive?
استعادة ذكرياتها أم البقاء على قيد الحياة؟
(Benevolent and Kind)
(طيب ورحيم)
Your Highness, do you feel anything?
صاحب السمو، هل تشعر بأي شيء؟
No, I don't.
لا، لا أشعر.
That's all right. I'll use more force.
لا بأس. سأستخدم المزيد من القوة.
Still nothing.
لا يزال لا شيء.
Nothing.
لا شيء.
Still? That doesn't hurt?
لا يزال؟ ألا يؤلمك ذلك؟
Not at all.
على الإطلاق.
I...
أنا...
Well? That had to hurt, right?
حسنًا؟ كان يجب أن يؤلمك، أليس كذلك؟
Still nothing.
لا يزال لا شيء.
Your Highness, surely you felt that one...
صاحب السمو، بالتأكيد شعرت بذلك...
Give me a hand, Yuetao.
ساعديني، يوي تاو.
Yes, Your Highness.
نعم، صاحب السمو.
Come on.
هيا.
Here.
هنا.
Together. Follow my lead.
معًا. اتبعيني.
One, two, three.
واحد، اثنان، ثلاثة.
You must've felt that one!
لا بد أنك شعرت بذلك!
Nothing.
لا شيء.
Nothing?
لا شيء؟
I get it now.
لقد فهمت الآن.
I must have gotten the angle and pressure wrong.
لا بد أنني أخطأت في الزاوية والضغط.
Don't worry. I have another way.
لا تقلقي. لدي طريقة أخرى.
Jiufeng, help me with this.
جيوفينغ، ساعديني في هذا.
Come on!
هيا!
Here we go.
ها نحن ذا.
Follow my lead.
اتبعيني.
One, two, three.
واحد، اثنان، ثلاثة.
Your Highness! You're sweating!
سموك! أنت تتعرق!
But it's not hot today.
لكن الجو ليس حارًا اليوم.
Do you feel anything now, Your Highness?
هل تشعر بأي شيء الآن، سموك؟
No...
لا...
I... I really don't feel anything.
أنا... أنا حقًا لا أشعر بأي شيء.
Well, you should, Your Highness.
حسنًا، يجب أن تشعر، سموك.
Three.
ثلاثة.
Maybe a tiny bit.
ربما قليلًا.
Really? How about now?
حقًا؟ ماذا عن الآن؟
Yes, I'm feeling it.
نعم، أنا أشعر به.
Oh, thank goodness!
أوه، الحمد لله!
I'm exhausted.
أنا مرهق.
Finally!
أخيرًا!
I need some water.
أحتاج إلى بعض الماء.
Why did you guys stop? Continue.
لماذا توقفتم؟ استمروا.
You still want to continue?
هل ما زلت تريد الاستمرار؟
Well...
حسنًا...
Your Highness!
سموك!
Healing takes time.
الشفاء يحتاج إلى وقت.
We have to look at the long term.
علينا أن ننظر إلى المدى البعيد.
Your Highness.
سموك.
- I... - Your Highness.
- أنا... - سموك.
I know
أعلم
it's not about a moment.
الأمر ليس متعلقًا بلحظة.
It's about every moment.
الأمر متعلق بكل لحظة.
We have to keep going.
علينا أن نستمر.
Let's continue the treatment.
لنستمر في العلاج.
Hang in there, Your Highness!
تحمل، سموك!
Give me a hand.
ساعدني.
There we go.
ها نحن ذا.
- Jiufeng, hurry up! - You guys...
- جيوفينغ، أسرع! - أنتم يا رفاق...
Hurry, Jiufeng!
أسرع، جيوفينغ!
Aren't you all tired? I'm already exhausted.
ألستم متعبين؟ أنا بالفعل مرهق.
Not in the slightest.
ليس على الإطلاق.
- Anything for you to get better. - We should rest...
- أي شيء لتحسّن. - علينا أن نرتاح...
We don't mind a little fatigue.
لا نمانع قليلًا من التعب.
I need to relieve myself!
أحتاج إلى قضاء حاجتي!
Is that a coffin?
هل هذا تابوت؟
Why are you sitting on a coffin?
لماذا تجلس على تابوت؟
What are you talking about?
عم تتحدث؟
This is a special table for Guasha therapy.
هذه طاولة خاصة لعلاج الغواشا.
Guasha therapy?
علاج الغواشا؟
What about the cloud pattern?
ماذا عن النمط السحابي؟
You really think you're some miracle physician now?
هل تعتقد حقًا أنك طبيب معجزة الآن؟
Bilian's already moved into the residence.
بيليان قد انتقلت بالفعل إلى المقاطعة.
If I don't hurry up and heal Prince Jin's legs,
إذا لم أسرع في علاج ساقي الأمير جين،
how can I stay here?
كيف يمكنني البقاء هنا؟
True.
صحيح.
I pay my respects to Your Highness.
أقدم احترامي لسموك.
I believe there may be some issues
أعتقد أن هناك بعض المشاكل
with the prescription I wrote for His Highness today.
في الوصفة التي كتبتها لسموه اليوم.
I was hoping Your Highness could offer some guidance.
كنت آمل أن يقدم سموك بعض التوجيه.
Bilian.
بيليان.
If you think your prescription is flawed,
إذا كنت تعتقد أن وصفتك بها عيوب،
you should keep that to yourself.
يجب أن تحتفظ بذلك لنفسك.
Don't come here trying to show off.
لا تأتي هنا لمحاولة التباهي.
I would never dare.
لن أجرؤ أبدًا.
I upset you, Your Highness.
لقد أزعجتك، سموك.
It was my mistake.
كان خطأي.
But everything I have done for His Highness's recovery
لكن كل ما فعلته من أجل شفاء سموه
is out of concern for his health.
هو بدافع الاهتمام بصحته.
You cannot just ignore his condition.
لا يمكنك تجاهل حالته ببساطة.
Is it really me ignoring his health?
هل أنا حقًا من يتجاهل صحته؟
Or is it you trying to climb your way into power
أم أنت من تحاول التسلق إلى السلطة
by cozying up to him?
من خلال التقرب منه؟
All right.
حسنًا.
I must prepare today's Guasha treatment for him.
يجب أن أعد علاج الغواشا له اليوم.
Leave.
اغرب عن وجهي.
Do not bother me again.
لا تزعجني مرة أخرى.
Yes, Your Highness.
نعم، سموك.
Oh, and from now on,
أوه، ومن الآن فصاعدًا،
stop trying all these tricks to get close to him.
توقف عن محاولة كل هذه الحيل للتقرب منه.
I will look after his health.
سأعتني بصحته.
Is that clear?
هل هذا واضح؟
Please excuse me.
من فضلك اعذرني.
Was she crying just now?
هل كانت تبكي للتو؟
Did I go too far?
هل بالغت؟
She just wants you to feel guilty.
إنها تريد فقط أن تشعرك بالذنب.
She showed up
لقد ظهرت
first thing in the morning to annoy me.
في الصباح الباكر لإزعاجي.
How should I deal with her?
كيف أتعامل معها؟
Deal with her?
تتعامل معها؟
Kick her out of the residence!
اطردها من المقاطعة!
Your Highness.
سموك.
I think Her Highness has feelings for you, too.
أعتقد أن سموها لديها مشاعر تجاهك أيضًا.
Let's go.
لنذهب.
What is this, Aliya?
ما هذا، علياء؟
Your Highness.
سموك.
Let's try Guasha therapy today.
لنجرب علاج الجواشا اليوم.
Guasha therapy?
علاج الجواشا؟
Your Highness.
سموك.
I suspect the root of your leg issue
أشك أن جذر مشكلة ساقك
might not be in the leg itself.
قد لا يكون في الساق نفسها.
By treating a few key pressure points with this stone,
من خلال علاج بعض نقاط الضغط الرئيسية بهذه الحجرة،
clearing toxins and promoting blood flow,
إزالة السموم وتعزيز تدفق الدم،
we might find the real cause.
قد نجد السبب الحقيقي.
Jiufeng. Yuetao.
جيوفينغ. يوتاو.
Don't just stand there.
لا تقفوا هكذا.
Undress His Highness.
اخلعوا ملابس سموه.
I have to get undressed?
علي أن أخلع ملابسي؟
Of course.
بالطبع.
How are you feeling, Your Highness?
كيف تشعر، سموك؟
I feel surprisingly refreshed and clear-headed.
أشعر بتحسن وصفاء ذهني بشكل مفاجئ.
Aliya.
علياء.
This therapy
هذا العلاج
must be exhausting.
لا بد أنه مرهق.
Should we
هل ينبغي لنا
let Bilian help?
أن ندع بيليان تساعد؟
No.
لا.
Why let her come for no reason?
لماذا ندعوها دون سبب؟
(She just doesn't want anyone else getting close to me.)
(هي فقط لا تريد أن يقترب أحد آخر مني.)
Your Highness.
سموك.
I've prepared your medicine for today.
لقد أعددت دواءك لهذا اليوم.
Let me feed it to you.
دعني أطعمك إياه.
It's too hot.
إنه ساخن جدًا.
Blow on it for me first.
انفخ عليه أولاً من أجلي.
Yes, Your Highness.
نعم، سموك.
What was that for?
ما كان ذلك لأجله؟
Nothing.
لا شيء.
Take your time with your medicine.
خذ وقتك مع دوائك.
I'll be going now.
سأذهب الآن.
- Your Highness. - Leave.
- سموك. - اذهب.
But the medicine...
لكن الدواء...
I said,
قلت،
leave.
اذهب.
Yes.
نعم.
I'll leave the medicine here for you.
سأترك الدواء هنا لك.
Did I overdo it?
هل بالغت في الأمر؟
Not at all.
على الإطلاق.
(Elegance and Refinement) Her Highness is starting to care.
(الأناقة والرقي) صاحبة السمو بدأت تهتم.
What we want is for her anger
ما نريده هو أن يشتعل غضبها
to burn even hotter.
بشدة أكبر.
Although, Your Highness,
مع ذلك، صاحب السمو،
she looked rather unfazed just now.
بدت غير منزعجة للتو.
My medicine.
دواءي.
Right away.
على الفور.
(Still Waters Run Deep)
(المياه الهادئة عميقة)
Your Highness, as you instructed,
صاحب السمو، كما أوصيت،
I've had someone watching over Princess Aliya discreetly.
لقد أوكلت شخصًا بمراقبة الأميرة عليا بحذر.
She's been visiting
لقد كانت تزور
a place called Everything Guild quite frequently.
مكانًا يُدعى نقابة كل شيء بشكل متكرر.
We looked into it.
لقد بحثنا في الأمر.
Everything Guild has a reputation.
نقابة كل شيء لها سمعة.
They specialize in solving all kinds of personal troubles.
يتخصصون في حل جميع أنواع المشاكل الشخصية.
You mean she's got problems she needs solved?
تقصد أنها لديها مشاكل تحتاج إلى حل؟
I would not dare assume.
لن أجرؤ على الافتراض.
But every time she goes,
لكن في كل مرة تذهب،
she consults with a woman about medical knowledge.
تستشير امرأة حول المعرفة الطبية.
What woman?
أي امرأة؟
She's been treating difficult illnesses at the guild lately.
لقد كانت تعالج أمراضًا صعبة في النقابة مؤخرًا.
They say she's cured quite a few unusual cases.
يقولون إنها عالجت العديد من الحالات غير العادية.
There's even a line to get a consultation.
حتى أن هناك طابورًا للحصول على استشارة.
Prepare the carriage.
جهزوا العربة.
We're going to meet her.
سنذهب لمقابلتها.
Understood.
مفهوم.
(Benevolent and Kind)
(اللطيف والطيب)
Bilian.
بيليان.
You prepared everything on this table.
لقد جهزت كل شيء على هذه الطاولة.
You should sit and enjoy it with us.
يجب أن تجلس وتستمتع معنا.
I do not dare.
لن أجرؤ.
I'm telling you to sit.
أنا أقول لك أن تجلس.
What is there to be afraid of?
ما الذي تخشاه؟
Thank you, Your Highness.
شكرًا، صاحب السمو.
Then, I will sit.
إذن، سأجلس.
Speaking of effort,
بالحديث عن الجهد،
Jiufeng,
جيوفينغ،
you've been His Highness's guard for years and protected him.
لقد كنت حارس صاحب السمو لسنوات وحميته.
You should be rewarded too.
يجب أن تكافأ أيضًا.
Come sit next to me.
تعال واجلس بجانبي.
I shouldn't, Your Highness...
لا ينبغي لي، صاحب السمو...
Why not?
لماذا لا؟
Come and sit.
تعال واجلس.
Jiufeng!
جيوفينغ!
You too, Yuetao.
أنت أيضًا، يوي تاو.
After serving us both for so long,
بعد أن خدمتنا كلينا لفترة طويلة،
you must be tired.
لا بد أنك متعب.
No need to stay standing.
لا داعي للبقاء واقفًا.
Join us.
انضم إلينا.
Yes, Your Highness.
نعم، سموك.
(Is she mad or just jealous?)
(هل هي غاضبة أم فقط غيورة؟)
Bilian, these are garlic chives.
بيليان، هذه بصل أخضر.
Have some.
تناولي بعضًا منها.
Thank you, Your Highness.
شكرًا، سموك.
May I, Your Highness?
هل يمكنني، سموك؟
Do you not know that garlic chives upset the stomach
ألا تعلمين أن البصل الأخضر يزعج المعدة
and have male-stimulating properties?
وله خصائص تحفيزية للذكور؟
They are not suitable for women.
إنها غير مناسبة للنساء.
Bilian.
بيليان.
As a fellow physician,
بصفتك طبيبة،
you should know that, right?
يجب أن تعرفي ذلك، أليس كذلك؟
I do,
أعرف،
but I dare not refuse His Highness's kindness.
لكنني لا أجرؤ على رفض لطف سموه.
If you were going to eat it anyway,
إذا كنت ستأكلينها على أي حال،
what was the point of asking me
فما الفائدة من سؤالي
that question just now?
هذا السؤال للتو؟
I was wrong.
كنت مخطئة.
I upset you, Your Highness.
أزعجتك، سموك.
I should not have said anything.
لم يكن عليّ أن أقول أي شيء.
Good.
جيد.
Give the chives to Jiufeng instead.
أعطي البصل الأخضر لجيوفينغ بدلًا من ذلك.
Eat up, Jiufeng.
تناوليها، جيوفينغ.
(A little help, Your Highness?)
(القليل من المساعدة، سموك؟)
Thank you, Your Highness.
شكرًا، سموك.
(Jiufeng's trick actually worked.)
(خدعة جيوفينغ نجحت بالفعل.)
Everyone, carry on eating.
استمروا في الأكل، جميعًا.
Bilian, this beef brisket is delicious.
بيليان، لحم الصدر هذا لذيذ.
Have some to keep up your strength.
تناولي بعضًا منه لتحافظي على قوتك.
Thank you, Your Highness.
شكرًا، سموك.
(Something must be wrong with Fu Chengjin's head today.)
(لا بد أن هناك شيء خطأ في رأس فو تشينغجين اليوم.)
This brisket looks good.
هذا اللحم يبدو جيدًا.
Have more of it, Yuetao.
تناولي المزيد منه، يوي تاو.
You too, Jiufeng.
أنت أيضًا، جيوفينغ.
(Looks like she is jealous.)
(يبدو أنها غيورة.)
Bilian.
بيليان.
This fish is my favorite dish in the residence.
هذه السمكة هي طبق المفضل في القصر.
You have worked hard these days treating my legs.
لقد عملت بجد هذه الأيام في علاج ساقي.
Eat more of this fish.
تناولي المزيد من هذه السمكة.
Be careful of the bones.
احذري من العظام.
Thank you, Your Highness.
شكرًا، سموك.
(Oh, no. Did I go too far?)
(أوه، لا. هل بالغت؟)
Your Highnesses...
سموكم...
Please don't be upset.
من فضلكم لا تنزعجوا.
It's all my fault.
كل هذا خطأي.
I know I am slow
أعلم أنني بطيء
and unworthy of Your Highness's kindness.
ولا أستحق لطف سموكم.
But if eating this upsets Her Highness,
ولكن إذا كان تناول هذا يزعج سموها،
then I'd rather kneel here
فأفضل أن أبقى راكعًا هنا
until the meal is over.
حتى تنتهي الوجبة.
Bilian.
بيليان.
If you want to kneel, go ahead.
إذا كنت تريد الركوع، فافعل.
I'm done with this meal.
لقد انتهيت من هذه الوجبة.
Let's go, Yuetao.
لنذهب، يوي تاو.
(She likes me a lot.)
(إنها تحبني كثيرًا.)
Jiufeng, I'm full too.
جيوفينغ، أنا أيضًا شبعت.
Let's go.
لنذهب.
(What is wrong with these people?)
(ما خطب هؤلاء الناس؟)
Back-shu points...
نقاط الظهر...
Under the spinous process of the 12th thoracic vertebra...
تحت العملية الشوكية للفقرة الصدرية الثانية عشرة...
Two finger-widths to the left and right...
عرض إصبعين إلى اليسار واليمين...
She doesn't even know how to do acupuncture?
ألا تعرف حتى كيفية الوخز بالإبر؟
Why is she studying a basic acupuncture chart?
لماذا تدرس مخطط الوخز بالإبر الأساسي؟
She doesn't seem like someone
لا تبدو كشخص
who knows medicine at all.
يعرف الطب على الإطلاق.
(Ginseng. Veratrum. Right herbal base.)
(الجينسنغ. الفيراتروم. قاعدة الأعشاب الصحيحة.)
(But that is too much ginseng.)
(ولكن هذا كثير من الجينسنغ.)
(No real physician would make a mistake like that.)
(لا يوجد طبيب حقيقي يرتكب خطأ كهذا.)
(Everything Guild)
(نقابة كل شيء)
Boil and take this daily. It will definitely help.
اغلي هذا وتناوله يوميًا. سيساعدك بالتأكيد.
- Thank you.
- شكرًا.
Let's go.
لنذهب.
Please be seated, Sir.
من فضلك اجلس، سيدي.
Manman!
مانمان!
What are your symptoms?
ما هي أعراضك؟
Miss. I've been feeling tightness in my chest and shortness of breath lately.
سيدتي. كنت أشعر بضيق في صدري وضيق في التنفس مؤخرًا.
Could you take a look at me?
هل يمكنك أن تنظري إلي؟
You are perfectly healthy.
أنت بصحة جيدة تمامًا.
No treatment is needed.
لا حاجة لأي علاج.
Actually, I came here today
في الواقع، جئت اليوم
to see you about a personal matter.
لأراك بخصوص أمر شخصي.
Personal?
شخصي؟
Do you want something
هل تريد شيئًا
to boost your virility?
لتعزيز قوتك الجنسية؟
No.
لا.
I came here specifically for you.
جئت هنا خصيصًا من أجلك.
For me?
من أجلي؟
You look familiar.
تبدو مألوفًا.
I saw you when I was flying kites
رأيتك عندما كنت أطير الطائرات الورقية
with Princess Consort Jin.
مع الأميرة القرينة جين.
What does that have to do with you?
ما علاقة ذلك بك؟
Are you two close?
هل أنتما قريبان؟
Why should I tell you?
لماذا يجب أن أخبرك؟
You seem quite skilled.
تبدو ماهرًا جدًا.
May I know who taught you?
هل يمكنني معرفة من علمك؟
You do not require my services.
أنت لا تحتاج إلى خدماتي.
Please leave.
من فضلك غادر.
You misunderstand.
أنت تسيء الفهم.
I just wanted to...
أردت فقط أن...
Sir.
سيدي.
Please.
من فضلك.
(What is with this guy?)
(ما خطب هذا الرجل؟)
(Every day,)
(كل يوم،)
(I'll get all kinds of people.)
(سألتقي بأنواع مختلفة من الناس.)
(Everything Guild)
(نقابة كل شيء)
Dear.
عزيزي.
Why are you asleep here?
لماذا أنت نائم هنا؟
Are you all right, Dear?
هل أنت بخير، عزيزي؟
Fang.
فانغ.
I want to do something for you too,
أريد أن أفعل شيئًا من أجلك أيضًا،
but
لكن
I'm not good enough.
لست جيدًا بما يكفي.
The only thing
الشيء الوحيد
I can do now
الذي يمكنني فعله الآن
is write stories.
هو كتابة القصص.
Dear,
عزيزي،
your fear of women is psychological.
خوفك من النساء نفسي.
You cannot rush through it.
لا يمكنك التعجل في التغلب عليه.
If we work on it together,
إذا عملنا عليه معًا،
we will get through it.
سنتمكن من تجاوزه.
Look at this.
انظر إلى هذا.
(Ji Mo's Treatment Plan)
(خطة علاج جي مو)
I have put together
لقد أعددت
a comprehensive treatment plan for you.
خطة علاج شاملة لك.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
We are supposed to be doing therapy, right?
من المفترض أن نكون في جلسة علاج، أليس كذلك؟
Exactly.
بالضبط.
And I am your treatment plan.
وأنا خطة علاجك.
The treatment means
العلاج يعني
closing the distance between us.
تقليل المسافة بيننا.
And what does the treatment involve?
وماذا يتضمن العلاج؟
Well...
حسنًا...
I'll poke your face with a finger in week one.
سأضغط على وجهك بإصبعي في الأسبوع الأول.
We'll hold hands
سنمسك بأيدينا
and go for a walk in week two.
ونذهب في نزهة في الأسبوع الثاني.
Hug in week three.
نعانق في الأسبوع الثالث.
As for week four...
أما بالنسبة للأسبوع الرابع...
I'll keep that a secret for now.
سأحتفظ بذلك سرًا في الوقت الحالي.
I'll head back now.
سأعود الآن.
I'm not going to make it to week four.
لن أتمكن من الوصول إلى الأسبوع الرابع.
You're here, Dear.
أنت هنا، عزيزي.
Fang.
فانغ.
I think we should skip this whole therapy thing.
أعتقد أننا يجب أن نتخطى هذا العلاج بأكمله.
Absolutely not.
بالتأكيد لا.
Come here.
تعال هنا.
I will do it myself.
سأفعل ذلك بنفسي.
- Sit. - Alright.
- اجلس. - حسنًا.
Now, look into my eyes.
الآن، انظر في عيني.
Don't move.
لا تتحرك.
One, two, three, four.
واحد، اثنان، ثلاثة، أربعة.
Very good.
جيد جدًا.
Keep it up.
استمر على هذا النحو.
Five, six.
خمسة، ستة.
Relax your head and shoulders.
أرخِ رأسك وكتفيك.
Focus on your breathing.
ركز على تنفسك.
Once you focus on your breath,
بمجرد أن تركز على تنفسك،
you will start to feel the blood and energy flow through your body.
ستبدأ في الشعور بتدفق الدم والطاقة في جسدك.
Now,
الآن،
close your eyes.
أغمض عينيك.
I feel much better.
أشعر بتحسن كبير.
We should call it a night!
علينا أن ننهي الليلة!
Wait!
انتظر!
We have not even started yet!
لم نبدأ بعد!
Fang, what are you...
فانغ، ماذا تفعل...
You tried to dodge treatment. You are a dead man.
حاولت أن تتجنب العلاج. أنت رجل ميت.
No... It's just that things have been really busy at the academy.
لا... فقط الأمور كانت مشغولة جدًا في الأكاديمية.
You're still making excuses.
ما زلت تقدم الأعذار.
Now, onto treatment method number two.
الآن، إلى طريقة العلاج الثانية.
There's a second method?
هل هناك طريقة ثانية؟
Are you sure this is treating me
هل أنت متأكد أن هذا يعالجني
and not just traumatizing me further?
وليس فقط يزيد من صدمتي؟
Are you questioning my medical skills?
هل تشكك في مهاراتي الطبية؟
I'm warning you.
أنا أحذرك.
Do not doubt my abilities.
لا تشك في قدراتي.
(Serene Breeze and Scenic Splendor)
(نسيم هادئ وجمال طبيعي)
Princess Consort Jin is all name and no substance.
الأميرة الزوجة جين كلها اسم بلا جوهر.
His Highness must be lonely.
يجب أن يكون سموه وحيدًا.
Noble Consort is right.
الزوجة النبيلة على حق.
(Blissful Passion) I'll warm His Highness's body and heart.
(شغف سعيد) سأدفئ جسد سموه وقلبه.
Your Highness, I've prepared your medicine.
سموك، لقد أعددت دوائك.
Just leave it there.
فقط اتركه هناك.
Yes, Your Highness.
نعم، سموك.
You've been overworking yourself lately.
لقد كنت تعمل بشكل مفرط مؤخرًا.
I worry you might forget to take your medicine.
أخشى أن تنسى تناول دوائك.
Might I stay and serve it
هل يمكنني البقاء وتقديمه
to you personally?
لك شخصيًا؟
I see it's too stuffy for you.
أرى أن الجو خانق بالنسبة لك.
Bilian.
بيليان.
Why not take that entire outer robe off?
لماذا لا تخلعين الرداء الخارجي بالكامل؟
Yes, I understand.
نعم، أنا أفهم.
I have no regrets.
ليس لدي أي ندم.
No regrets, truly?
لا ندم، حقًا؟
Jiufeng.
جيوفينغ.
Your Highness.
سموك.
She thinks it is too hot here.
هي تعتقد أن الجو حار جدًا هنا.
Take her to the garden to cool off.
خذيها إلى الحديقة لتبرد.
And get someone to keep an eye on her.
واحضري شخصًا ليراقبها.
Do not let her come back
لا تدعيها تعود
for at least two hours.
على الأقل لمدة ساعتين.
Perfect. The mosquitoes have been bad lately.
ممتاز. البعوض كان مزعجًا مؤخرًا.
Someone needs to feed them.
شخص ما يحتاج لإطعامهم.
Come along.
تعالي معي.
Your Highness...
سموك...
Your Highness!
سموك!
Your Highness.
سموك.
It's time for your medicine.
حان وقت تناول دوائك.
Aliya.
علياء.
Do I have to take this medicine every single day?
هل يجب أن أتناول هذا الدواء كل يوم؟
It is unbearably bitter.
إنه مر بشكل لا يطاق.
Your Highness.
سموك.
Bitter medicine works best.
الدواء المر هو الأفضل.
Drink it. I am watching you.
اشربيه. أنا أراقبك.
Aliya,
علياء،
this was just delivered by Bilian.
هذا تم تسليمه للتو من قبل بيليان.
She specifically told me
لقد أخبرتني بشكل محدد
this cannot be taken with other medicines.
أن هذا لا يمكن تناوله مع أدوية أخرى.
I will just drink this one first...
سأشرب هذا أولاً...
There.
ها هو.
Bilian's medicine is gone.
دواء بيليان انتهى.
Now can you take your real medicine?
الآن، هل يمكنك تناول دوائك الحقيقي؟
Why do I feel so warm all of a sudden?
لماذا أشعر بالدفء فجأة؟
Why did you stop?
لماذا توقفت؟
Continue. Finish them all.
استمر. أنهيها جميعًا.
Why are you
لماذا أنت
looking at me like that?
تنظر إليّ بهذه الطريقة؟
I'm watching you take your medicine.
أنا أراقبك وأنت تتناول دوائك.
Three more bowls to go. Come on.
ثلاثة أطباق أخرى. هيا.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
I'm not sure why,
لست متأكدًا من السبب،
but my heart's been racing
لكن قلبي كان يخفق
after I took that medicine.
بعد أن تناولت ذلك الدواء.
And I feel gorgeous.
وأشعر بأنني رائعة.
What do you think?
ما رأيك؟
You look
تبدين
exquisite.
رائعة.
Thanks.
شكرًا.
A gentleman can't prey on another's moment of weakness!
لا يمكن للرجل النبيل أن يستغل لحظة ضعف الآخر!
A gentleman can't not prey on another's moment of weakness.
لا يمكن للرجل النبيل إلا أن يستغل لحظة ضعف الآخر.
You can just marry me.
يمكنك ببساطة أن تتزوجني.
I...
أنا...
We're already married, aren't we?
نحن بالفعل متزوجون، أليس كذلك؟
You are my consort.
أنت قريني.
No, I'm not.
لا، لست كذلك.
I'm Manman.
أنا مانمان.
Bilian.
بيليان.
The audacity of her!
يا لجرأتها!
♪The clouds stretch endlessly across the sky♪
♪تمتد السحب بلا نهاية عبر السماء♪
♪Looking down at eyes that gaze into the distance♪
♪أنظر إلى عيون تحدق في البعيد♪
♪Time keeps moving on♪
♪الزمن يستمر في التقدم♪
♪Whose footprints are left behind?♪
♪من الذي ترك آثاره خلفه؟♪
♪It's more than just the courage to yearn♪
♪إنه أكثر من مجرد الشجاعة للشوق♪
♪It's destined that we cannot be close♪
♪مقدر لنا ألا نكون قريبين♪
♪Loving you is a secret♪
♪حبك سرٌّ♪
♪Afraid of disturbing you and then you'd distance yourself♪
♪أخشى أن أزعجك ثم تبتعد عني♪
♪Endlessly♪
♪بلا نهاية♪
♪How I wish I could dive into the sea♪
♪كم أتمنى أن أغوص في البحر♪
♪And gently rest♪
♪وأستريح بلطف♪
♪It's to soothe the reason for your heart's pain♪
♪إنه لتهدئة سبب ألم قلبك♪
♪If everything could overcome all barriers and fall in love♪
♪إذا كان كل شيء يمكن أن يتغلب على كل الحواجز ويقع في الحب♪
♪Even the cloud and sea could be together♪
♪حتى السحاب والبحر يمكن أن يكونا معًا♪
♪Forget how far from shore and how dangerous it is♪
♪انسَ مدى البعد عن الشاطئ ومدى خطورته♪
♪We can't see♪
♪لا نستطيع أن نرى♪
♪If distance can't tear us apart and it's not hard to endure♪
♪إذا كانت المسافة لا يمكنها أن تفصلنا وليس من الصعب تحملها♪
♪Our tears will stay together♪
♪دموعنا ستبقى معًا♪
♪Don’t forget the love♪
♪لا تنسَ الحب♪
♪They could never have♪
♪الذي لم يستطيعوا الحصول عليه أبدًا♪